

Software Engineer

joashagesa@yahoo.com

0

in 💆





About

My name is Joash Agesa, a bachelor of computer software Engineering student and a freelance software engineer. My passion for software lies with dreaming up ideas and making them come true with elegant interfaces. I take great care in the experience, architecture, and code quality of the things I build.

I am also an open-source enthusiast. I love how collaboration and knowledge sharing happens through open-source and I am happy to see what I do could eventually feedback to the community and industry.

Projects

CodeGround ♥ 7

An Educational Online Code Editor powered by AI Documentation



100 days Challenge ♥ 7

100 days of design challenge



Beeetle 7

An embeddable Chat Wigdet with ai powered conversation

More Projects...

Work Experience

VIRTUALWEB TECHNOLOGIES Software Engineer

Jun 2023 - Present | Remote

In Department

- Developed mobile applications driving business operations
- Created Script Automations for the business cloud monitoring
- Designed the Cloud Access Portal for end users

SiafuSocial Ltd. Technical Lead

May 2023 - Nov 2023 | Nairobi, Kenua

In Product R & D and Engineering Architecture Department

- Collaboratively remediated 120+ software anomalies, contributing to user-centric features via reusable code.
- Verified and optimized feasibility of 100+ UI/UX designs for 2+ applications.
- Implementing security measures such as encryption, authentication, and authorization.
- Optimizing backend code and database queries to improve application performance and response times.

Stacks

Frontend TypeScript, JavaScript, Vue, Nuxt, React, Next.js, React Native, Vite

Backend Node, MongoDB, MySQL, Serverless, Nginx, Docker, Dokku

Mobile Android, Kotlin, PWA

DevOps Firebase, AWS, Azure, AliCloud

Languages Python, Java, C/C++, C#, Go

Education

Computer Software Engineering, Bachelor of Science - BS, Kirinyaga University

Sep 2019 - Sep 2023

Languages

Swahili (Native speaker), English (Fluent), Japanese (Beginner)

Online Version

Last updated at February 16th 2024, 6:50:55 pm